Quan T. Cao Email: q.caaoo@gmail.com Cell: (240)529-8218

SKILLED HOSPITALITY MANAGEMENT & TEAM DEVELOPMENT SPECIALIST

Seasoned hospitality manager driven to excel within the hospitality industry with experience encompassing 8 years of management in the industry and proven success as a team leader. Assertive self-starter, competent in business improvements, and increasing sales/volume. Key strengths include excellent interpersonal communication skills, advanced knowledge of handling administration including control of labor and foot costs, knowledge of steps of service/restaurant decorum, and the ability of employing, training, maintaining, and overseeing staff.

EXPERIENCE

Opening Senior Manager, Declaration (PRG Hospitality)

2018 to Present

Washington, DC

(Overlapping position with below)

Senior leadership based position focused on launching a newly opening 134 seat restaurant. The position was initially tasked with employing and training a full front of house team as well creating standard operating procedures and systems. Once established, the position was responsible for overseeing all facets of the front of house and handling all administrative tasks necessary for the restaurant.

- Exceeded initial sales forecasts of \$40,000/month by over an average of \$12,000 monthly through various methods of training and marketing.
- Maintained an opening front of house team of 27 with a turnover rate of 14.8% in the first eight months of the restaurant launch against an estimated 50% turnover rate.
- Effectively operated the front of house as the only and primary manager by streamlining administrative tasks and service
 operations as well as successfully elevating staff to take on additional responsibilities such as supply ordering, shift
 supervising, and repair/maintenance.

Restaurant Manager, LINCOLN Restaurant (PRG Hospitality)

2017 to Present

Washington, DC

Leadership based position focused on elevating front of house standards and operations in a 235 seat restaurant with a specialty in profit/loss administration and private events.

- Reduced overall labor costs by 2.5% within eight months without compromising service or efficiency in the front of house by redistributing areas of responsibility and creating a culture focused on teamwork.
- Established and maintained a culture within the management team centered around hands-on leadership in the dining room, improving the overall morale and motivation of the front of house team leading to a 27% turnover rate against the previous year's 55% turnover rate.
- Led and operated a growing private events program generating ~\$850,000 in 2016 (21% of total revenue) and ~\$975,000 in 2017 (24% of total revenue) in 2017.

Company Restaurant Manager, Pho & Grill LLC

2010 to 2016

Olney, MD / Gaithersburg, MD

Management based position focused on the procurement of securing and maintaining local community business, ensuring exceptional service, and delivering consistently outstanding food in a multi-establishment restaurant company.

- Employed and maintained an outstanding front of the house team of an average 25 member size with a turnover rate of 12% over the duration of 5 years in a new location (2011-2016).
- Instrumental in the improvement of gross sales by ~40% within 5 years following the opening of the restaurant's second location through proper team management and supervision while establishing the development of interpersonal relationships with customers.

EDUCATION

Associates of Arts (STEM Core); Montgomery College, Rockville, MD; 2012